# STEPHEN CHARLES

I'm a proficient pythonista with a background in mathematics, astrophysics and computer science. Particular expertise in managing machine learning pipelines with large data sets involving time series analysis, computer vision and NLP, in addition to interpersonal skills from a range of hospitality roles. Take a look at my Portfolio and GitHub for examples of recent projects.

#### EMPLOYMENT

FEB 2022 - Now

Innovative Technologies - Manchester - Remote

Position

Machine Learning Engineer

Python, Pytorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Git, Bash • ICU performs accurate age verification to automate associated policy and allow access to age restricted purchases and premises, through an ensemble of various ML algorithms.

- Implemented bespoke methods from cutting edge research in SVM's, CNN's, and Bayesian Linear Regression which allow for statistically robust age verification.
- Designed a system by which spoof detection was achievable through the use of belief propagation and anomaly detection.
- Deployed trained models in resource-constrained environments.
- Worked remotely in an agile, communicative, and self-directed manner as part of a collaborative, interdisciplinary, diverse, and geographically-dispersed team.

 $\mathbf{J}_{\mathbf{UNE}} - \mathbf{S}_{\mathbf{EPT}} \ \mathbf{2020}$ 

Position

Data Scientist, Analytics Intern

Tableau, SQL, Python, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

- Performed large-scale data analysis to extract useful business insights.
  - Identified the ones which were actionable, suggesting recommendations, and influenced the direction of the business by communicating the results to cross-functional groups.
  - Classified leads so that the team could work on the most valuable cases, and suggested improvements in the tools and techniques to help scale the team.
  - Created dashboards with Tableau on data obtained via SQL queries.

#### EDUCATION

Ост 2021 – 2022

Data Science - University of Bath

Distinction, Master of Computer Science

Statistics for Data Science - Probability and statistics, with a focus on translating real-world problems into a mathematical framework in data science contexts.

Machine Learning - Covered both supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms from Bishop, including how to develop, evaluate and deploy trained models. The second semester involved advanced techniques focused on neural networks with both regression and classification.

Reinforcement Learning - Implemented various agents to solve environments from Sutton & Barto, including Dynamic Programming and Temporal Difference methods.

Bayesian Machine Learning - Implementing approaches such as bayesian inference, importance sampling monte carlo, and confidence interval predictions using bambi.

 $O_{CT} 2020 - 2021$ 

Astronomy and Astrophysics – University of Manchester

Distinction, Master of Physics

Research

Published a program to facilitate the data acquisition and analysis pipeline for TESS automatically, dubbed firefly (the best Sci-fi show!), which applies nested sampling (dynesty) to find best fit variables (TransitFit) between the host star and exoplanet.

SEPT 2016 - 2020

Mathematics with Computer Science – University of Nottingham

Upper Second-Class Honours, Master of Mathematics

Research

Dissertation involved working with python to numerically solve spherical cavitation bubble collapse.

**Sept 2014 - 2016** 

Space Engineering - Loughborough College

A-Levels

Mathematics  $A^* \cdot Further Mathematics A \cdot Physics A \cdot Engineering A$ 

SEPT 2009 - 2014

A specialised course focused on Engineering with guest lectures at the Space Centre in Leicester.

Secondary School – Loughborough College

GCSE's

Mathematics A\* · Further Mathematics A · Physics A · Biology B · Chemistry B · English A · English Literature A  $\cdot$  Astronomy A

## GENERAL TECH STACK

## Awards and Qualifications

Languages	Python, C++, SQL, IATEX	2022	
PACKAGES	Numpy, Pandas, SciPy, AstroPy	2022	AWS DeepRacer Student
ML PACKAGES	Sklearn, Tensorflow, PyTorch	2021	Kaggle Competitions
Data Viz	Tableau, Seaborn	2020	Tableau Desktop Specialist
Scientific	Matlab, R, Fortran, Mathematica	2016	Full UK Driving Licence
CLOUD	GCP, AWS	2015	Grade 8 Violin

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Hayes, J J C, E Kerins, J S Morgan et al. (2021) "TransitFit: an exoplanet transit fitting package for multi-telescope datasets and its application to WASP-127 b, WASP-91 b, and WASP-126 b", 1–14.

## ACADEMIC WORK EXPERIENCE

Scholarship - National University of Singapore **A**UTUMN 2018

Scholarship Obtained a scholarship to study a crash course in Korean language for 5 weeks and to learn about

the culture and history of the changing landscapes of Singapore. Upon completion, applied to spend

the Autumn semester here successfully.

SEPT 2017 - 2019 Physics Outreach – The University of Nottingham

I began, on a voluntary basis, promoting physics via social media which eventually evolved into a

paid role in which I mediated with events staff in the department to ensure successful participation.

Part of the role was ensuring inclusivity, and how best to target minority groups.

Magical Maths – St Mary's Catholic Primary School, Nottingham **SUMMER 2018** 

Organisation of weekly sessions to promote mathematics to primary school children, in line with

the national curriculum.

Research Intern - Space Research Centre, The University of Leicester **SUMMER 2014** 

During my first college year I gained work experience at the University of Leicester Space Research

Centre, assisting in the development of an astrobiology rock-sampling tool called SPLIT for use on

## Voluntary Positions and Responsibilities

<b>2020 - Now</b> Researcher	SPAR – University of Manchester Actively contributing to exoplanet detection in the spearnet collaboration.	2021 - Now Researcher	ART-AI – University of Bath Collaborating with a large research group with an aim to educate interdisciplinary professional experts to make the best,
Interests			and safest, use of artificial intelligence.
Рнотодкарну	Avid adventurer and keen astronomer. This hobby pushes the	Music Art	Self taught Guitar, Piano, Violin.  Into optical illusions like the works of

boundaries of my interest in both. Escher, Bridget Riley etc. Exploring the peaks, lakes and Love the classics, Jules Verne, H.P. LITERATURE

> anywhere with hills. Love to spend Lovecraft, H.G. Wells etc.

weeks away camping. Into Sci fi and anything spacey! GENERAL

#### References

Dr. Eamonn Kerins Prof. CJ Harris Dr. John Holt NAME TITLE Senior Lecturer Research Professor Research Engineer EMAIL University of Manchester University of Southampton University of Leicester Department of Physics Department of Engineering Department of Physics PhD PhD, DSc, FREng, Fellow PhD, FREng